《蝙蝠侠》
(哥谭市)
谢谢你 嗨 我要去亚道夫大饭店
Thank you. Hi. I'd like to go to the Adelphi Hotel.
- 抱歉 - 对不起 车子是我叫的
- Excuse me. - I'm sorry. This is my cab.
我先来的呀!
I was here first!
天呀
Oh, God.
计程车!
Taxi!
走路过街吧
Let's go across. Come on.
到那边去叫 走
We'll get one down the road. Hurry.
拜托 哈洛 快叫车呀?
For God's sake, Harold, can we please just get a taxi?
我正在叫计程车!
I'm trying to get a...Taxi!
方向错了!
We're going the wrong way!
吉米 收起来 像土观光客似的
Put that away. We'll look like tourists.
嗨 甜心
Hi, honey.
在这我们永远叫不到车 我们到第7街再说
We'll never get a cab. Let's cut over to Seventh.
- 第7街在那边 - 我知道方向!
- Seventh is that way. - I know where we are!
先生 赏一块钱吧
Hey, mister. Give me a dollar.
- 快走 - 怎么样? 一块钱而已
- Come on. - How about it? One dollar.
你聋了吗? 不会说英语?
Are you deaf? You don't speak English?
快呀! 到这里
Come on! Up here.
女士
Hey, lady...
看小孩的份上 不要叫
do the kid a favor. Don't scream.
收获不少
Hey, all right.
美国运通信用卡
American Express card.
"出门别忘此卡"
"Don't leave home without it."
滚远点
Get out of here.
说实话 伙计 我不喜欢这里
Let's beat it, man. I don't like it up here.
怎么 你有恐高症?
What, are you scared of heights?
不知道 强尼的下场使我害怕
I don't know. After what happened to Johnny Gobs...
强尼是喝醉酒从屋顶掉下去摔死的 没什么好伤心的
Look, man, Johnny Gobs got ripped and took a walk off a roof. No big loss.
错了 伙计 我听说的不是这样
No, man, that ain't what I heard at all.
听说被蝙蝠侠抓走的
I heard that the Bat got him.
蝙蝠侠? 得了吧?
The Bat? Give me a break, will you?
从4楼摔下去 身体里一点血也没有
Five stories. Straight down. There wasn't no blood in the body.
胡扯 人行道上一片红
No shit. It was all over the pavement.
- 我要走了 - 闭嘴 听我说
- I'm getting out of here, man. - Shut up, man. Listen to me.
根本没有蝙蝠侠
There ain't no Bat.
你不该用枪打那个孩子的
You shouldn't have turned the gun on that kid.
你究竟要不要你的钱? 大嘴给我闭上! 闭嘴
You want your cut of this money or not? Now shut up! Shut up.
别杀我!
Don't kill me!
别杀我! 兄弟
Don't kill me! man.
别杀我!
Don't kill me!
我不杀你 有事请你帮忙
I'm not going to kill you. I want you to do me a favor.
带个话给你所有朋友
I want you to tell all your friends about me.
你是什么东西?
What are you?
我是蝙蝠侠
I'm Batman.
对全美国人而言
Across this nation...
哥谭市就是犯罪的代名词
the words "Gotham City" are synonymous with crime.
街头暴力充斥 政府官员束手无策
Our streets are overrun, our public officials are helpless.
身为市长 我保证扫清犯罪的根源
As mayor, I promise to root out the source of this corruption...
包斯卡尔格里森
Boss Carl Grissom.
并由新任地方检查官
Now, our new District Attorney, Harvey Dent...
哈维丹特执行
will carry out that promise.
哈维
Harvey
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢 布格市长 谢谢
Thank you, Mayor Borg. Thank you.
哥谭市民们
People of Gotham City...
我一向言简意赅
I'm a man of few words.
不过却一言九鼎 言出必行
But those words will count, and so will my actions.
高登局长说
Police Commissioner Gordon has informed me...
他已经找出那些
that he has targeted those businesses...
为黑社会的非法营业
suspected of fronting for the syndicate in this city.
这星期之内
Before the week is out...
我们将全面大扫荡
we are going to knock down their doors...
直捣魔窟
and shed the light of the law on that nest of vipers.
只要大家团结 便可以建设成一个理性高尚的城市
Together, we can make this city safe for decent people.
高尚的人不该住本市
Decent people shouldn't live here.
换个地方会更快乐
They'd be happier someplace else.
听说卡尔是个铁腕硬汉
Pretty tough talk about Carl.
你放心好了
Don't worry about it.
那个小丑敢碰格里森一下 早就被我吊死了
If this clown could touch Grissom, I'd have handed him his lungs by now.
格里森要知道你我的事
If Grissom knew about us...
你也不会好过的
he might hand you something.
你别往脸上帖金了
Don't flatter yourself, angel.
他已年迈花甲 缺了我 他控制不了本市
He's a tired old man. He can't run this city without me.
再说嘛
And besides...
他也不知道
he doesn't know.
你真的毫不在乎? 杰克
You don't worry about anything, do you, Jack?
帅哥
You look fine.
我没问你
I didn't ask.
对 好好保重
Yeah. Hanging on.
你别说 让我猜
No. Let me guess.
一只巨大 超级动物 像只蝙蝠
Giant, menacing, supernatural form. Kind of like a bat.
没错 上面怎么回事?
That's it. What are they seeing up there?
喝了通乐
They're drinking Drano.
有点怪异 警官
It's a little weird, Lieutenant.
谢谢你的情报
Thanks for the tip.
要命 又是诺克
Christ. Knox.
你好 艾哈特警官 听说蝙蝠攻击人类
Hello, Lt. Eckhardt, I hear we just had us another Bat attack.
一个月之内连续八起?
That's what, eight sightings now in just under a month?
听说局长下令彻查 是真的吗?
I hear the Commissioner's even opened a file. True?
抱歉 诺克 这两个人踩香蕉皮跌死的
Sorry, Knox. These two slipped on a banana peel.
我没骗你 是只巨大的蝙蝠!
I'm telling you, man, a giant bat!
继续走
Keep move.
最后别登在报上 诺克
Don't be writing this stuff in the newspaper, Knox.
以免毁了报社的声名
It'll ruin your already useless reputation.
警官 全镇的游民都吓得魂不守舍的
Lieutenant, every punk in this town is scared stiff.
知道他们怎么说吗? 说他刀枪不入
Do you know what they say? They say he can't be killed.
专喝人血
They say he drinks blood.
- 还说 - 我说你满嘴狗臭屁 诺克
- They say... - I say you're full of shit, Knox.
这句话可以引述
You can quote me on that.
哥谭市真的有只6尺蝙蝠吗?
Is there a 6-foot bat in Gotham City?
他是领警察薪水的吗?
And if so, is he on the police payroll?
扣了税以后 年薪多少?
And if so, what's he pulling down, after taxes?
带给你的小点心 艾哈特
Brought you a little snack, Eckhardt.
- 干嘛不去广播? - 闭嘴听我说
- Why don't you broadcast it? - Shut up and listen.
哈维丹特盯上了咱们一家前卫公司
Harvey Dent has been sniffing around one of our front companies.
我的地盘 任何问题我会处理
That's my territory. If there's a problem, I deal with it.
你的问题也是我们的
Your problems are our problems.
我只对格里森负责 不对神经病
I answer to Grissom, not to psychos.
为什么 艾哈特 你该为未来想想
Why, Eckhardt, you ought to think about the future.
你以为你能接管? 你最好别做梦 杰克
You mean when you run the show? You ain't got no future, Jack.
你是神经加三级 格里森心里有数
You're an A-1 nut-boy, and Grissom knows it.
考虑清楚哟
Better be sure.
瞧吧?
See?
愿意的话是可以做出明智的决定
You can make a good decision when you try.
你在哪过夜的?
Where you been spending your nights?
我不管预算如何 我要举办游行
I don't care how deeply in debt this festival is, I want a parade.
有热狗 汽球 整个策划
I want hot dogs, balloons, the whole schemer.
热热闹闹地庆祝2百周年纪念日
We're gonna celebrate this 200th anniversary proudly and publicly.
还是庆祝破产吧
We may be celebrating in bankruptcy court.
债务已经25万 还没看见半个汽球
This festival's $250,000 in the red and we haven't seen one balloon.
只要把人找来 生意自然会有
You fill this square with people, and the businesses will come back here.
很多人会怕的躲起来 市长
I think a lot of people might stay away, Mayor. They're scared.
有了格里森干地方检察官 就不用怕了
They won't be scared when you get Grissom in that courthouse.
我承诺过 记得吗?
I promised that, remember?
欢迎吸血爵士光临
Welcome, Count Dracula.
- 最近有没大脚的消息? - 嘿 诺克
- Had any sightings of Bigfoot lately? - Hey, Knox...
- 你的连载已被蝙蝠侠取代了 - 垃圾就该如此处理
- they buried your story on the Batman. - That's what they do to garbage.
可以得普立兹新闻奖的
This is Pulitzer Prize stuff, guys.
诺克 有东西给你
Hey, Knox. I got something for you.
真好笑 獠牙下该画几滴口水的
Very funny. You should have a little bit more gore under the fangs, though.
傻屌一个
What a dick.
哈罗 长腿姊姊
Hello, legs.
我在看你的报导
I'm reading your stuff.
我在看你的美腿
Well, I'm reading yours.
嗨 我是维琪瓦尔
Hi, I'm Vicki Vale.
维琪瓦尔 流行和大都会 摄影师
Yeah, photographer. Vogue, Cosmo. Yeah.
对 想拍我裸照的话 得把镜头拉长
Listen, if you want me to pose nude, you're gonna need a long lens.
其实我正在拍战争的东西
Actually, I was in the Corto Maltese.
拍那玩意会有危险的
A girl could get hurt doing this stuff.
什么风把你吹来的?
So, what brings you here?
来看哥谭市野生动物的
I'm here to see some of the wildlife in Gotham City.
野生? 比方说?
Wildlife? Like what?
比方说蝙蝠
Like...bats.
- 谁派你来的? - 没人 真的
- Who sent you? - Nobody, really.
我喜欢你的报导
I just loved your story, and...
我喜欢蝙蝠
I like bats.
真的?
really?
我的照片加上你的报导 保证得奖 考虑看看
My pictures, your words. Pulitzer Prize material. Just think.
算你有远见 也是唯一相信我的人
Okay, you're a visionary. You're also the only one who believes me.
我需要确凿的证据
I need something tangible.
高登有档案 他连我电话都不接
Gordon's got a file on this. I can't even get him on the phone.
他会参加布鲁斯韦恩慈善义演 他会去吧?
Bruce Wayne's benefit. He'll be there, right?
对 只是名单上没有我 没有
Yeah. I don't seem to be on the guest list. No.
对 对
Yes. Yes.
维琪 你愿意嫁我吗?
Yes. Vale, will you marry me?
- 不要 - 请我吃饭?
- No. - Will you buy me lunch?
- 有可能 - 我食量不大
- Maybe. - I eat light.
万一
Say this...
这个王八蛋
son of a bitch...
查出艾克斯化学厂和我们有关
makes a connection with us and with Axis Chemicals.
真不知后果会如可?
What kind of damage are we looking at?
万一被他查到了 咱们真的完蛋了
If he ties us in with Axis Chemicals, we're dead and buried.
我们该立刻采取行动
We should move immediately.
我建议突击该厂
I say we break into the place...
把办公室捣烂
trash the office...
把纪录毁掉 宣称是工业间谍干的
and make off with the records and say it was industrial espionage.
聪明 这么做才对 事实上
Smart thinking. That's the way to go. In fact...
我要你亲自指挥这个行动
I'd like you to handle this operation personally.
我?
Me?
哈罗 甜心
Hello, sweetheart.
你不介意去隔壁等吗?
I wonder if you'd mind waiting in the next room?
没事 各位 谢谢光临 没事了
That's all, gentlemen. Thank you.That's all.
卡尔
Carl...
可否派别人去?
can we get somebody else to do this?
我受不了化学味
The fumes in that place...
杰克
Jack.
这次行动关系重大
It's an important job.
我需要个信得过的人
I need someone I can trust.
你是我的左右手
You are my number one guy.
你
Now...
别忘了
don't forget...
你的幸运牌
your lucky deck.
朋友
My friend...
你就要走运了
your luck is about to change.
警察局
Police Department.
请接艾哈特警官
Get me Lt. Eckhardt.
需要我效劳吗? 先生
Can I help you, sir?
谢谢 多谢你 你真好
Thanks. Thank you very much. That's very nice of you.
赏你的
Here you go.
- 晚上好 小姐 - 人多了点
- Good evening, ma'am. - A little crowded.
对不起 对不起
Excuse me.Excuse me...
请教布鲁斯韦恩是谁?
Could you tell me which of these guys is Bruce Wayne?
我没把握
I'm not sure.
还是得谢你
Thanks anyway.
是呀
Yeah
谢谢
Thank you.
哦 当然
Oh, certainly.
快下注!
Bet!
8点 我一丢就是8点
Eight. I can make that eight.
- 我一丢就是8点 - 请下注
- I can make that eight. - Place your bets, please.
局长! 高登太太 你真漂亮
Commissioner! Mrs. Gordon, you look lovely.
局长真的有蝙蝠侠的档案?
How about that rumor that Commissioner's got a file on the Batman?
不是真的吧?
That's not true, is it?
诺克 没有什么蝙蝠
Knox, for the ninth time, there is no Bat.
有的话早抓走了
If there were, we would find and arrest him.
你确认吗? 跟我坦白说 局长
Would you confirm him? Be straight with me, Commissioner.
- 手气还好吧? - 糟透了
- How you making out? - Not good at all.
丹特先生 我喜欢你的领带
Mr. Dent, I love that tie.
我们正在谈飞行义警的事 你的立场如何?
We were discussing the pros and cons of winged vigilantes. What's your stand?
诺克先生 本市的问题已经够多了
Mr. Knox, we have enough problems in this city...
没暇为鬼力乱神之事操心了
without worrying about ghosts and goblins.
没错 我无法否认
Pardon me, but that's not a denial.
失陪一下 我马上回来
Excuse me, dear. I'll be back.
有谁要公开发表一下的?
Isn't anybody going to go on record?
- 阁下 好棒的西装 - 无以置评
- Your Honor, great suit. - No comment.
- 什么事? 罗勃 - 匿名情报
- Robert, what's up? - Anonymous tip.
纳皮尔扫荡了艾克斯厂
Napier's cleaning out Axis Chemicals.
为什么没人告诉我? 是谁负责的?
Why wasn't I told about this? Who's in charge?
- 艾哈特 - 真要命!
- Eckhardt, sir. - Oh, my God!
咱们走
Come on, let's go.
高登先生?
Commissioner Gordon?
等一下 起居间 餐厅 还是弹药库
Wait, wait. Living room, dining room, arsenal.
瞧瞧这些玩意
Look at this stuff.
这家伙是谁?
Who is this guy?
一个人道主义者 居然收集这种玩意
He gives to all these humanitarian causes, and then collects all this stuff.
还不是为了交女人 她们喜欢他的慈善舞会
He probably does it to get chicks. They like him for his big charity balls.
别忘了他的存款数字
Don't leave out his very large bankroll.
越有钱 人越不值钱
Now, remember, the more they've got, the less they're worth.
那么他八成是全美国 价格最底的人
Then this guy must be the most worthless guy in America.
你瞧这个 他八成是稻草人之王
Check this out. He must have been King of the Wicker People.
这是哪来的?
Where'd this come from?
我不知道
I have no idea.
是日本的
It's Japanese.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
我打日本买的
Because I bought it in Japan.
- 你是谁? - 抱歉 布鲁斯韦恩
- Who are you? - Sorry. Bruce Wayne.
亚历山大诺克
Alexander Knox.
我看过你的报导 佩服之至
I read your work. I like it a lot.
谢了 捐一点吧?
Thanks. Can I have a grant?
- 维琪瓦尔 - 嗨
- Vicki Vale. - Hi.
- 布鲁斯韦恩 - 没搞错吧?
- Bruce Wayne. - Are you sure?
对 错不了
Yeah, this time.
我看过你战争的作品 对吧?
I've seen your photographs from Corto Maltese, haven't I?
对
Right.
你的眼光独到
You've got a wonderful eye.
该说是两只的
Some people think she has two.
这栋房子好壮观 希望能有机会拍
This is an amazing house. I'd like to shoot it sometime if you...
韦恩先生 我们还需要几箱香槟 可以吧?
We need to open a few more cases of the champagne. Will that be all right?
当然 请便
Sure. Go ahead.
开几箱? 6箱?
Open, what, six? Six?
- 6箱好 - 可以
- Six is good. - Okay.
好的 6箱 谢谢
That's great, six, thanks.
你会在哥谭市待一阵吗?
Anyway, you gonna be staying in Gotham for a while?
我很愿意 我对亚历山大的蝙蝠报导很有兴趣
I'd love to. I'm intrigued by Alex's giant bat stories.
对 蝙蝠侠
Oh, right. The Batman.
可以调剂一下战争的火药味 对吧?
That's a little bit light after the war in Corto Maltese, isn't it?
- 你是干哪一行的? - 哦 我
- What do you do for a living? - Well, I'm involved...
高登局长想告辞了
Sir, Commissioner Gordon was compelled to leave.
好的 谢谢你
Okay, thank you.
相当出乎意料 先生
Very unexpectedly, sir.
两位恕我告退了?
Will you two excuse me?
请这边走 先生
I think perhaps this way, sir.
对
Yeah
阿福 前面还需要些酒
Alfred, they need some more wine in the front room...
戴尔太太还需要一份菜单
and someone named Mrs. Daley needs a copy of the menu.
对了 捐点钱给诺克
And give Knox a grant.
很高兴跟你聊 韦恩
Nice talking with you, Wayne.
富人
The rich...
知道他们为什么怪异吗? 因为有钱经得起
You know why they're so odd? Because they can afford to be.
你看这面镜子
Look at this mirror.
该叫布鲁斯浮华的
Maybe it should be Bruce Vain.
- 罗勃 什么事? - 匿名情报
- Robert, what's up? - Anonymous tip.
纳皮尔扫荡了艾克斯厂
Napier's cleaning out Axis Chemicals.
只要逮了他 格里森也跑不了
If we could put our hands on him, we'd have Grissom.
为何没人告诉我? 谁负责的?
Why wasn't I told about this? Who's in charge?
- 艾哈特 - 要命!
- Eckhardt, sir. - Oh, my God!
咱们走
Come on, let's go.
你看清楚了 就是他
All right. Take a good look. This is the guy.
(通缉犯: 杰克纳皮尔)
看个清楚
All right, get a good look.
格杀勿论 懂我意思吧?
Shoot to kill. You know what I mean?
好了 出发吧
All right, let's move out.
我们被摆道了 各位
We've been ratted out here, boys.
小心
Watch it.
不准动!
Freeze!
你 左边 你去右翼 快
You, left. You take the right. Move it.
怎么回事?
What the hell's going on?
你想干什么? 泄底吗?
What are you trying to do? Blow the collar?
这儿由我负责 不是卡尔格里森
I'm in charge here, not Carl Grissom.
我是高登局长 我要抓活口
This is Commissioner Gordon. I want him taken alive.
重覆一次 谁开枪打伤杰克 就得对我负责
I repeat. Any man who opens fire on Jack Napier will answer to me.
放我下来!
Let me down!
哦 天呀!
Oh, my God!
他在那边!
He went that way!
到那边的窄道上看看
See if you can get up on the catwalk on that side.
你守那一边 务必小心 千万别大意
You take that side. Be careful. Be very careful.
老天爷!
Jesus!
放了他 否则我就杀高登!
Let him go, or I'll do Gordon!
好漂亮的行头
Nice outfit.
快呀 杰克 咱们走!
Come on, Jack, let's go!
快点! 杰克!
Come on! Jack!
艾哈特!
Eckhardt!
替未来想一下
Think about the future.
他妈的 已经到手了
God damn it, we had him.
不准动!
Hold it right there!
- 那小子是谁? - 不知道
- Who is this guy? - I don't know.
查明真相前 别说出去
Until we find out, keep a lid on it.
等等 如果真没蝙蝠侠 是谁把杰克丢进硫酸中?
Wait. If there's no Bat, then who dropped this guy, Napier, into the acid?
自杀呀? 等等 我要录音
Suicide? Wait, I want to get this on tape.
喂?
Hello?
他挂了 你找到了什么?
He hung up. What have you got?
这是市内 这是艾克斯厂
Here's the inner city, there's Axis Chemicals...
这是露面的地点
and here's the sightings so far.
蝙蝠侠可能有固定的飞行路线
Maybe Batman has some kind of flight pattern or something.
这是我的想法
That's all I can think of.
非常好 这样好了
This is very good. I'll tell you what...
今晚先请你去吃饭 然后去散个步
tonight, first I'll take you to dinner, then we'll walk the trail.
不行 我和布鲁斯韦恩先约好了
No can do. I got a date. With Bruce Wayne.
韦恩! 韦恩! 不行!
Wayne! Wayne! Oh, no!
你又能怎么样?
How about you?
那家伙是个呆头鹅 配不上你
The guy's a stiff. He's a rich stiff, but you could do much better.
谢谢你的关心 再见
Thanks for being so concerned. Bye.
汤还好吧?
How's the soup?
对不起?
Excuse me?
我说汤 怎么样?
The soup. How is it?
太好了
It's great.
盐传过来好吗?
Could you pass the salt?
好的
Sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
我家好找吗?
Did you have a hard time finding the house?
- 很容易 没问题 - 好
- No, it was no problem. - Good.
你喜欢在这儿吃饭?
Do you like eating in here?
对
Yeah.
老实说我以前没来过这里
You want to know the truth, I don't think I've ever been in this room before.
你想出去吗?
Do you want to get out of here?
对
Yes.
布鲁斯主人小时候
There was young Master Bruce...
骑着一匹小灰马跟着我
leading his gray pony with me on its back...
像一袋老土豆 全身是泥 脚踝扭伤正在治疗
like a sack of old potatoes, covered in mud and nursing a sprained ankle.
那是我有生第一次也是最后一次 教他骑术
That was the first and last time I gave him a riding lesson.
那一次让他一直很尴尬
I think I've embarrassed him for long enough.
我该去睡了
I'm off to bed.
拜托 不用动 我明早再收拾
Please, leave everything. I'll tidy up in the morning.
- 晚安 小姐 - 晚安 阿福
- Good night, miss. - Good night, Alfred.
- 晚安 先生 - 晚安 阿福
- Good night, sir. - Good night, Alfred.
他真好 他很爱你
He's really wonderful. He loves you a lot.
阿福是很棒 连袜子都得靠他找
Alfred's great. I couldn't find my socks without him.
他令我想起我爷爷
He sort of reminds me of my grandfather.
你们很亲吗?
Were you close to him?
对 我常和他及奶奶 一起过暑假
Yeah, I used to spend summers with him and my grandmother.
他们住在湖边 虽比不上你家 可是
They had a house on the lake. Nothing like this, but...
很好玩
it was fun.
- 不错嘛 - 对
- That sounds nice. - Yeah.
你的家人呢?
What about your family?
其实 只有阿福
Actually, Alfred is my family.
这里的一切似乎跟你很不衬
This house and all this stuff really doesn't seem like you at all.
有些东西很像我
Some of it is very much me.
有些不是
Some of it isn't.
餐厅绝对不像
That dining room is definitely not you.
对 没错
The dining room isn't.
(手术室)
- 看看结果吧 - 好
- Let's see how we did. - Yeah.
哦 天啊!
Oh, my God!
镜子
Mirror.
拿镜子来!
Mirror!
你知道神经已完全毁了
You understand that the nerves were completely severed.
你也看到我用什么工具了
You see what I have to work with here.
这地方到处是楼梯
There's an awful lot of stairs in this place.
两条腿快断了
My feet are killing me.
好了
Okay.
我有点醉了 你却没事
I feel a little drunk. And you're not anything.
再一杯下肚就要飞了
One drink and I'm flying.
你害怕飞行不成?
Why are you afraid of flying?
是你吗 小甜点?
That you, sugar bumps?
你是谁?
Who the hell are you?
是我
It's me.
"小甜点"
"Sugar bumps."
杰克
Jack.
谢天谢地 你没死! 我听说你
Thank God, you're alive! I heard you'd been...
烫死了?
Fried?
你是这么听说的?
Is that what you heard?
为了一个娘们陷害我
You set me up over a woman.
一个娘们!
A woman!
你八成是疯了
You must be insane.
免了吧
Don't bother.
你命狗屎不值!
Your life won't be worth spit!
我已经死了一次
I've been dead once already.
感觉很自由
It's very liberating.
不妨当做是一种治疗
You should think of it as therapy.
杰克 听我说
Jack, listen.
或许咱俩可以谈个条件
Maybe we can cut a deal.
杰克?
Jack?
杰克早死了 朋友
Jack is dead, my friend.
叫我
You can call me...
丑客
Joker.
你也看得出来
And as you can see...
我比过去更快乐了
I'm a lot happier.
光荣的日子
What a day.
哥谭市呀
Gotham City.
我一见你就笑
It always brings a smile to my face.
"飞行怪胎
"Winged freak...
人心惶惶"
terrorizes..."
还没见识过老子呢
Wait till they get a load of me.
我有个妙计 到我家吃午饭?
I've got an idea. How about lunch at my place?
给你看些照片
I'll show you some photos.
好呀 好
Sure. Okay.
等一下 我不能去 我抽不出空
Wait a minute. No, I can't. I can't make it.
好吧 晚点再去
Okay, we'll do it later in the day.
不行
Hold on a second.
晚点也不成 今天有个重要的会议
I can't make it then, either. I've got a very important meeting today.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
没什么
Nothing's wrong.
真的 我只想离开几天
Really. I've just got to go out of town on business for a few days.
- 好吧 等你回来再说 - 好的
- Okay, we'll do it when you get back. - All right.
我该走了 不早了
I got to go. I'm late.
再见
Bye.
老天
Jesus.
阿福
Alfred.
- 真高兴又见到你 小姐 - 彼此
- It's nice to see you again, ma'am. - Nice to see you, too.
等你们回来再说罗
I'll talk to you guys when you get back.
回来? 可能要好一阵哟
Back, Miss Vale? We're going to be here for quite a while.
好吧 再见
Well, bye.
甜心
Honey...
你绝不相信我今天的遭遇
you'll never believe what happened to me today.
各位 情况就是如此 在格里森露面之前
So, gentlemen, that's how it is. Until Grissom resurfaces...
我是代理董事长
I'm the acting president.
我决定在周年纪念日
And I say, starting with this anniversary festival...
攻击哥谭市
we run this city into the ground.
为什么不等格里森决定?
Why don't we hear this from Grissom?
对
Yeah.
他奸笑个什么劲?
And what's with that stupid grin?
上帝对我很眷顾
Life's been good to me.
如果我们拒绝呢?
What if we say "no"?
东尼呀
Well, Tony...
没人喜欢战争
nobody wants a war.
生意不成仁义在 我们握手言和
If we can't do business, we'll just shake hands and that'll be it.
是吗?
Yeah?
没错
Yeah
还有电呢
I got a live one here.
本镇今晚有的瞧罗
There'll be a hot time in the old town tonight
东尼一定火冒三丈罗
Antoine got a little hot under the collar.
你疯了
You're crazy.
你可曾听过一笑治百病 这句话?
Haven't you ever heard of the healing power of laughter?
- 给我滚! - 你们都听到了 走! 快走!
- Now get out of here! - You heard him. Let's go! Move it!
你们想清楚
You think it over.
快走 快 滚出去
Let's go, come on. Get out of here.
快走!
Move it!
巴勃
Bob
你去镜报跟踪诺克
I want you to go down to the Globe, follow that reporter Knox.
带着照相机去
Take your camera.
看他对蝙蝠侠知道多少
See what he knows about this Batman.
还有巴勃
And, Bob...
切记 你
remember, you...
你是我的左右手
are my number one guy.
是的
Yes, sir.
我的朋友
Your pals...
都不算坏人
they're not bad people.
我们不妨
Maybe we...
给他们几天时间考虑一下
ought to give them a couple of days to think it over.
不行?
No?
现在就杀他们?
Grease them now?
好吧
Okay.
你是个大奸包 洛泰里
You are a vicious bastard, Rotelli.
你死了活该
I'm glad you're dead.
I'm glad he's dead.
我正需要
I need that.
我快对你失去信心了 我以为咱们是一伙的
I'm losing confidence in you. I thought we were a team.
是你的私人问题吧?
This wouldn't be a personal issue for you, would it?
我只要你尽到责任
I just want you to do your job.
我是在尽责任
I am doing my job.
我也是 我在保护伙伴
Me, too. I'm protecting my partner.
档案中查不出任何照片或资料 他是什么人?
There's nothing in these files. No photos, no histories, no nothing. Who is this guy?
管他的?
Who cares?
别管布鲁斯韦恩了 我要采访蝙蝠侠
Forget about Bruce Wayne. I'm on to Batman.
他们马上就要出发
They should be out here any second.
我等着听他们如何解释
I can't wait to hear the explanation for this one.
他来了 老兄
Here he comes, man.
你公证什么文件?
What is this affidavit you filed?
格里森把所有事业都交给你了?
Grissom gave you all his businesses?
格里森先生以私情委托我
Mr. Grissom asked me, as a personal favor...
接管他的事业 直到他回来为止
to take over the operation of his businesses until he returns.
这倒是个大人情 你俩关系八成不错
That's a pretty big favor. You two must have been very close.
很不错
Very close.
小时候一起吃过牢饭?
Did you do a little time together as children?
我方的会计会查阅的 委任书是合法的
Our accountants are looking into it. We assure you, the affidavit is legitimate.
我闻到墨水味 你能证明吗?
I smell fresh ink, guys. You can prove all this?
我胡扯些什么? 他当然能了
What am I asking? Of course you can.
我们有证人 格里森的签名完全合法
We have witnesses. Grissom's signature is perfectly legitimate.
是合法的
It is legitimate.
我看见了 我在场
I saw it. I was there.
全部看见了
I saw it all.
他伸出死手
He reached up with his dead hand...
用鲜血签的
and signed it in his own blood.
他用这支笔写的
And he did it...with this pen.
哈罗 文尼 我是你宾果叔叔呀
Hello, Vinnie. It's your uncle Bingo.
该还债了
Time to pay the check.
笔
The pen...
的确比剑有力
is truly mightier than the sword.
趴下!
Get down!
帮派火拼会影响周年纪念活动吗?
Doesn't this gang war dampen the city's plans for the 200th anniversary festival?
活动照常举行 警方会阻止那些歹徒
The festival opens. The police are gonna stop these gangsters.
丹特先生 你对蝙蝠侠是黑社会组织
Mr. Dent, what do you think about the theory...
的说法有何意见?
that the mysterious Batman is a mob enforcer killing these men?
恕不奉告
I don't have any comment.
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
人穿蝙蝠装
Can somebody tell me what kind of a world we live in...
这成了什么世界呀
where a man dressed up as a bat...
抢尽我的风头?
gets all of my press?
本市需要通个便!
This town needs an enema!
阿福
Alfred.
给我杯水好吗?
May I have a glass of water?
你回来令我很安慰
I'm relieved that you're home, sir.
瓦尔小姐来电话 她很关心呢
Miss Vale telephoned. She was rather concerned.
她来过之后 好像安心多了
I feel that there's a certain weight that lifts when she is here.
阿福
Alfred...
你干脆娶她算了?
why don't you marry her?
我没有这个打算
That's not exactly what I had in mind, sir.
不要
No.
我此刻无法思考这件事
I can't go on with that right now.
现在不想
If not now...
几时?
when?
不知道
I don't know.
我听说杰克纳皮尔还活着
I just found out Jack Napier's still alive.
接管了格里森的事业 我需要一切警方的资料
He's running Grissom's men. I need all the information the police have on him.
- 是的 - 谢谢你
- Yes, sir. - Thank you.
阿福
Alfred.
她很棒 对吧?
She is great, isn't she?
对
Yes, sir.
- 市政府 诺克 - 嗨
- City room, Knox. - Hi.
- 帮我查点资料好吗? - 说吧
- I want you to check something out for me. - Sure.
查一下珍珠和菲力浦街 有什么不寻常的
Find out what's so special about the alley at Pearl and Phillips Streets.
- 珍珠和菲力浦? - 对
- Pearl and Phillips? - Yeah.
没问题
You got it.
好
Okay.
再见了
Okay, bye.
韦恩先生
Mr. Wayne.
事情这么多 时间不够用的
So much to do and so little time.
照片
The photos.
那个废物是谁?
Who's that loss?
诺克
It's Knox.
丑领带 没格调
Bad tie. No style.
一切暂停!
Stop the press!
- 她是什么人? - 维琪瓦尔
- Who is that? - That's Vicki Vale.
和诺克一起的摄影师
She's the photographer who's working with Knox.
这姑娘有味道
That girl has style.
乖乖隆地咚!
Jesus marimba!
这么迷人的娘们
A lovely beast like that running around...
哪个男人见了不来劲的
could put steam in a man's strides.
她和一个叫韦恩的人一起
She's dating some guy named Wayne.
她快要升级了
She's about to trade up.
很难剪得齐
It's hard to stay inside the lines.
我就要有
I'm about...
新女人了 巴勃
to get a new girl, Bobby.
我此时哈的要死
I'm of a mind to make some mooky.
- 电话簿 - 遵命
- Phone book. - Yes, sir.
事情这么多
So much to do...
时间总觉不够
and so little time.
(艾克斯化学公司)
你运出一百万桶了吗?
Have you shipped a million of those things?
是的
Yes, sir.
全运出去 咱们要改变整个规模!
Ship them all! We're going to take them out a whole new door!
再十秒钟
Ten seconds to transmission.
五 四
Five, four...
三 二 一
three, two, one.
音乐
Cue music.
贝琪
Cue Becky.
晚上好 当今的流行界
Good evening. The fashion world was stunned today...
因模特儿甘蒂华克 和艾曼达吉勒之死而震惊
by the sudden deaths of models Candy Walker and Amanda Keeler.
据说死因是强烈的过敏反应
Cause of death has been attributed to a violent allergic reaction...
当局也不排除药物致死的可能性
although authorities have not ruled out the possibility of drug use.
彼得
Peter.
市长今天在揭幕式中宣布
And plans continue for the city's 200th birthday...
周年活动按计划举行
as Mayor Borg announced today at the unveiling...
这是刚送来的
This just in.
哥谭市一家美容院 今天发现一连发生
Three mysterious deaths at a beauty parlor...
三起神秘死亡事件
At a beauty parlor in Gotham were discovered today.
到底是怎么搞的?
What the hell's going on?
贝琪 这种行为太
Becky, this is hardly the...
贝琪
Becky.
摄影机关掉
Kill the camera.
我是蕾妮 在新闻摄影棚
This is Rene on the news floor.
我需要一些镇静剂
I need some paramedics up here now.
新上市丑客产品!
New and improved Joker products!
内含秘密成份
With a new secret ingredient.
含笑素!
Smylex!
怎么回事?
What is this?
我们再继续
Now, let's go over...
无偏见的口味
to our blind taste test.
我爱那个丑客
Love that Joker.
- 从哪来的? - 不知道
- Where's it coming from? - I don't know.
他不太快乐 他使用的是X牌的
He don't look happy. He's been using brand X.
有了新的丑客牌之后
But with new and improved Joker brand...
我脸上再度展露笑容
I get a grin again...
永不消失
and again.
还有美丽的古铜色
That luscious tan...
宝红双唇
those ruby lips...
还有自然的发色 只有殡仪馆的人才知道
and hair color so natural, only your undertaker knows for sure.
我懂你说些什么:
I know what you're saying:
"我到哪去买这么好的货品? "
"Where can I get these fine, new items? "
妙处就在这 其实你已经买过了!
That's the gag. Chances are, you bought them already!
我爱丑客
Love that Joker.
别忘了
So, remember...
随时保持笑容
put on a happy face.
- 你要的资料 先生 - 谢谢你
- The information you requested. - Thank you.
杰克纳皮尔 15岁 以致命武器攻击
"Jack Napier, assault with a deadly weapon, age 15.
"心理测试结果
"Results of psychological profile...
心智失常 智慧极高 情绪极度不稳
violent mood swings, highly intelligent, emotionally unstable.
性格取向包括科学 化学和艺术"
Aptitudes include science, chemistry, and art."
化学
Chemistry.
- 阿福 我们去购物 - 好的
- Alfred, let's go shopping. - Yes, sir.
(化妆品带来恐慌)
又有六人死亡 然而丑客的致命武器 仍无线索
Six new deaths, with no clues as to the Joker's deadly weapon.
下毒的货品有哪些?
And what is the pattern?
食物 酒精 美容及卫生产品?
Foods, alcohol, or beauty and hygiene products?
古龙水 漱口水 腋下除臭剂?
Cologne, mouthwash, underarm deodorant?
最糟的是 找不出固定的模式来
Or worse yet, there may be no pattern.
警方继续搜索哥谭市各个购物中心
The search goes on through Gotham's shopping nightmare.
活动照计划举行 即使要我用猎枪 也在所不惜
We are going to have a festival if I have to get a shotgun to get people there myself.
你听清楚了吗? 活动照常举行!
Do you hear the words coming out of my mouth? The festival is on!
你马上去查出那个疯子 用的是什么毒药
And you find out what this madman is poisoning us with.
快去 懂了吗?
And fast. Do you read me?
我们正在研究 我需要各方面的支援
We're working on it. I need all the help I can get.
布鲁斯 嗨 我是维琪
Bruce, hi. It's Vicki.
抱歉 我可能晚十分钟才能到博物馆
I'm sorry, but I'm gonna be 10 minutes late to the museum.
见面再谈 再见
I'll see you when I get there. Bye.
先生 是瓦尔小姐的口信
Sir, a message from Miss Vale.
她会迟到十分钟
She'll be 10 minutes late in meeting you at the museum.
好的 谢谢你 等一下 阿福
Okay, fine, thank you. Wait a minute, Alfred.
我今天没有约她
I'm not meeting her today.
杰克 你去哪呀?
Jack, where are you going?
我要去创作艺术 亲爱的
Daddy's going to make some art, darling.
对不起 韦恩先生的桌位?
Excuse me. Mr. Wayne's table?
他还没到
Yes. He hasn't arrived yet.
桌子已摆好了
We have a table waiting.
好的
All right.
瓦尔小姐 这是刚送到的
Miss Vale, this just arrived for you.
(马上戴上去)
各位!
Gentlemen!
我们来扩展一下见识 劳伦斯
Let's broaden our minds. Lawrence.
刮个胡子
Give him a shave.
泰伦斯 画笔
Terence, brush.
(丑客在此)
一元钞票
The one-dollar bill.
等一下!
Hold it!
我蛮喜欢这一幅的 巴勃 别戳破
I kind of like this one, Bob. Leave it.
可以摘下来了
You can take that off now, I think.
你很漂亮 很有古典美
You're beautiful in an old-fashioned kind of way.
我有办法让你更现代化
But I'm sure we can make you more today.
是你的手提箱吗?
Is that your portfolio?
我约了人来看我作品的
I'm meeting someone who wants to see my work.
废物
Crap.
废物废物
Crap...
这是好作品
Now that's good work.
骷髅 尸体
The skulls, the bodies.
被你一拍就很惹眼 艺术我虽不懂 我很喜欢
You give it such a glow. I don't know if it's art, but I like it.
让我告诉你 我的想法吧 美人
Let me tell you what I'm thinking about, sweetie.
我有一天正在洗澡
I was in the bath one day...
突然发觉 自己天生就是个伟人
when I realized why I was destined for greatness.
你知道一般人多注重外表
You know how concerned people are about appearances.
这个人迷人 这个人很丑
This is attractive, that is not.
那一切都过去了 我现在的一切是别人梦想不到的
That is all behind me. I now do what other people only dream.
我创作艺术 直到有人死为止
I make art. Until someone dies.
懂吧?
See?
我是世界第一个全自动化杀人艺术家
I am the world's first fully-functioning homicidal artist.
你想干什么?
What do you want?
我的照片印在一元钞票上
My face on the one-dollar bill.
笑话
You must be joking.
我的表情像吗?
Do I look like I'm joking?
不像
Well...
听我说
Listen.
我们不能和平凡人去比 我们是艺术家
We mustn't compare ourselves to regular people. We're artists.
比方说 我拿一幅作品跟你挑战
For instance, let me challenge you with a little piece I did.
巴勃 爱莉雪
Bob. Alicia.
你用照片纪录我的作品
You will take pictures and record my work.
跟我加入前卫艺术之列
You will join me in the avant-garde of the new aesthetic.
杰克 你说我可以看你修改画的
Jack, you said I could watch you improve the paintings.
出了点问题
I'm in trouble now.
她干嘛戴面具?
Why is she wearing a mask?
其实只是张草图
She's just a sketch, really.
爱莉雪 坐下 告诉她你为何戴面具
Alicia, sit down. Show the lady why you wear the mask.
你知道 瓦尔小姐 她和我有共同的人生哲学
You see, Miss Vale, Alicia's been made over in line with my new philosophy.
所以她和我一样
So now, like me...
是幅活动艺术品
she is a living work of art.
我不是毕卡索 不过你会喜欢吗?
I'm no Picasso, but do you like it?
太棒了
It's great.
要我帮什么忙?
So, what can I do for you?
唱首歌 跳支舞
A little song, a little dance.
蝙蝠侠的头吊在绳子上
Batman's head on a lance.
告诉我 你知道多少
Tell me, what do you know about...
我对他一无所知
I don't know anything about Batman.
真的吗?
Really?
咱俩热呼一下如何?
Well, how about a little "you and me"?
你疯了
You're insane.
我以为我是双鱼宫的 来吧
I thought I was a Pisces. Come on.
咱们交合一下
Let's make up. Have a little...
闻闻我的小牡丹
whiff of my posy.
救命呀!
Help me!
我快要溶化了!
I'm melting!
我快要溶化了! 救命呀! 我快要溶化了!
I'm melting! Help me! I'm melting!
嘣
Boo.
抱紧
Hold on.
他哪来的好玩意?
Where does he get those wonderful toys?
- 上车 - 哪一辆?
- Get in the car. - Which one?
快走
Let's go.
盾甲
Shields.
你多重?
How much do you weigh?
108磅吧
About 108, I think.
抓稳
Hold on.
看见我腰带上的东西吗? 抓住
See that thing on my belt? Grab it.
无论如何 别放手
Whatever you do, don't let go.
没有血
No blood.
那家伙是谁?
Who is this guy?
查一下皮夹
Check his wallet.
- 等等 - 那是什么?
- Wait a minute. - What is that?
是胄甲 他终究还是个人
Some kind of body armor. He's human after all.
面具脱掉
Take off the mask.
开枪!
Shoot her!
盾甲开
Shields open.
你不只108磅
You weigh a little more than 108.
- 真的? - 快走
- Really? - Let's go.
停
Stop.
我们去哪?
Where are we going?
小心点
Be careful.
蝙蝠
Bats.
生存能力很强
They're great survivors.
- 这是什么玩意? - 警方搞错了
- What is all this? - The police have got it wrong.
他们以为只有一种产品
They're looking for one product.
丑客在上百种货品中下毒
The Joker's tainted hundreds of chemicals at the source.
整批货都会有毒
Then whole shipments of products would be poisoned.
我们都会死
And we'd all be dead.
不会
No.
成份混合后毒药才会生效 喷发水单独不起作用
The poison only works when components are mixed. Hairspray won't do it alone.
但若和香水 唇膏混合 就会有毒了
But hairspray mixed with lipstick and perfume will be toxic, and untraceable.
你怎么知道的?
How did you figure this out?
这个拿去报社
Take that to the press.
这么做有点困难
I might have some trouble with that.
很多人认为 你和丑客一样危险
A lot of people think you're as dangerous as the Joker.
他是丧心病狂
He's psychotic.
也有人这么说你
Some people say the same thing about you.
什么人?
What people?
面对现实吧
Well, I mean, let's face it.
你并非正常人 对吧?
You're not exactly normal. Are you?
这也不算个正常世界
It's not exactly a normal world, is it?
为何带我来此?
Why did you bring me here?
你大可自己送去报社的
You could have sent that stuff to the press yourself.
说的对
You're right.
你拥有我想要的东西
There is something else you have that I want.
什么?
What?
他把底片拿走了
He took the film.
是啊
Yeah.
你去哪了? 还好吧? 要我过去吗?
Where have you been? Are you all right? Do you want me to come on over?
不要了 亚历山大
No, Allie.
如果我现在送新闻来 赶得上晚间版吗?
If I bring something to you, can we make the evening edition?
还来得及 好爆吗?
Just barely. Is it hot?
对 保证大爆
Yeah, it's real hot.
好的 再见
Yeah, bye.
- 校对! - 是的?
- Copy! - Yes, sir?
避免下列的合用情形:
Avoid the following combinations:
除臭剂不能与婴儿粉 喷发水和唇膏并用
Deodorants with baby powder, hairspray, and lipstick.
安全产品在哥谭市上空 大量空投
Safe products are flying in as Gotham City goes on a forced fast.
市民对这位蝙蝠侠 不知如何看待
And all of Gotham is wondering what to make of Batman.
是友还是敌?
Friend or foe?
我眼中长出一根刺
I have given a name to my pain...
蝙蝠侠
and it is Batman.
要对抗痛苦首需力量 巴勃
You must possess strength to inflict pain, Bob.
有只飞鼠待宰
We've got a flying mouse to kill...
我要磨爪以待
and I want to clean my claws.
瓦尔小姐又来电了
Sir, Miss Vale called again.
你目前的行为
Dare I suggest that your present course of action...
只会强化她的决心?
might simply strengthen her resolve?
她很机巧
She is quite tenacious.
说的对
You're right about that.
恕我直言 也很特别 不妨考虑对她说实话
And if I may say so, quite special. Perhaps you could try telling her the truth.
来了
Coming.
嗨
Hi.
可以进去吗?
May I come in?
好漂亮的房子
This is a nice apartment.
空间也好大
Lots of space.
我是来
Listen, I came over to...
- 澄清几件事的 - 你自以为是什么!
- clear a few things... - I don't know who you think you are!
- 你伤了我 - 我知道
- You hurt me. - I know.
我不断打电话给你 你却一直骗我! 骗我说要出城
I called you and I called you. And you lied! You lied about leaving town.
- 我告诉你原因吧 - 我告诉你好了!
- Let me tell you why. - Let me tell you!
你邀我吃饭
You invited me out, we went to dinner.
我以为彼此很投缘 我相信你
I thought we felt something. And I trusted you.
跟你睡觉 我不信自己这么做
I even slept with you. I can't believe I did that.
你却连个电话也不回 你八成是个变态
Then you wouldn't return my calls. You must be some kind of jerk.
你是个好女孩 我好喜欢你 不过你先闭嘴
You're a real nice girl and I like you a lot, but right now, shut up.
我有话要说
I have something I have to tell you.
你知道人的性格是多变的?
You know how people have different sides to their personality?
有时候
Sometimes...
不得不过另一种生活
a person will have to actually lead a different life.
我的天 你结婚了
Oh, my God, you're married.
我没结婚
No, I'm not married.
其实
You see...
我的生活很
my life is really...
复杂
complex.
好 你听着 你知道正常人一起床
All right, listen. You know how a normal person gets up and...
就下楼
goes downstairs...
吃早饭
and eats breakfast...
跟家人吻别
and kisses somebody good-bye, and goes to...
去上班 你懂
a job and, you know.
不懂
No.
不懂?
No?
好吧 听着
All right, look.
维琪 我要说的是
Vicki, what I'm trying to tell you is...
嘿 没关系
Hey, it's okay.
- 告诉我无妨 - 好的
- You can tell me. - Okay.
我要说的是
What I'm trying to tell you is...
其实
is a ...
- 我马上回来 - 好的
- I'll be right back. - All right.
想我吗?
Miss me?
你家真美 空间好大
Nice place you got here. Lots of space.
维琪 咱们得谈谈
Vicki, we really should have a talk.
真气人
I'm very upset.
我们吃过饭
We were having dinner.
我一向在美女面前一把罩
I was a man doing well with a beautiful woman.
你却一个抱歉也不说
And without so much as an apology...
就跟那个小瘪三走了
you ran off with that sideshow phony.
你知道
You know, Vic...
我最近发生了悲剧
I've recently had a tragedy in my life.
爱莉雪
Alicia...
跳窗自杀了
threw herself out of the window.
天呀
Oh, my God.
可是
But...
塞翁失马焉知非福
you can't make an omelet without breaking some eggs.
瓦尔小姐呀
Well, Ms. Vale...
窝里还有只公鸡呀?
another rooster in the hen-house?
简直令我伤心欲绝
Take thy beak from out my heart.
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
布鲁斯韦恩 对吗? ?
Bruce Wayne, n'est-ce pas?
大部份时候是
Most of the time.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我说给你听吧 杰克
Let me tell you about this guy I know, Jack.
下流 龌龊 专门害人
Mean kid. Bad seed. Hurt people.
我已经喜欢上他了
I like him already.
知道问题在那吗?
You know what the problem was?
他短路 疯狂
He got sloppy. You know, crazy.
他已经成不了气候了 满肚子烂肠烂肉
He started to lose it. He had a head full of bad wiring, I guess.
脑袋已经报销了
Couldn't keep it straight up here.
他是个
He was the kind of guy who...
不见棺材不流泪的人
couldn't hear the train until it was 2 feet from him.
知道他的下场吗?
You know what happened to this guy, Jack?
听着
Listen.
他犯了错
He made mistakes.
后来就发了疯! 你也想发疯吗?
Then he ended up with his lights out! Now you want to get nuts?
来吧! 大伙一起疯!
Come on! Let's get nuts!
告诉我件事
Tell me something, my friend.
可曾在月光下和魔鬼共舞过?
You ever dance with the devil in the pale moonlight?
什么?
What?
我经常这样问每一个枪下鬼
I always ask that of all my prey.
我只是喜欢听那种声音
I just like the sound of it.
不要随便挑人的针眼
Never rub another man's rhubarb.
为什么每次找你
Why is it every time we got company...
总是杀出程咬金来?
somebody always gets in the way?
我需要独处一下
I'll need a moment alone, boys.
我只是笑在脸上
I'm only laughing on the outside.
内心痛苦无比
My smile is just skin-deep.
但愿你看得透我
If you could see inside...
心在哭泣
I'm really crying.
你会陪我痛哭一场的
You might join me for a weep.
说了你也不信
You wouldn't believe it. You really wouldn't.
你乐得去享受 我却到处找你
While you were out entertaining, I've been here finding out about your street corner.
瓦尔
Vale
你朋友完蛋了
I think your friend Wayne is really screwed up.
还有更精彩的
More good news.
你瞧
Here.
(汤玛斯韦恩被害 儿子幸免)
我的天!
Oh, my God!
他父母在那被谋害
His parents were murdered in that alley.
所以他才会去那
That's why he went there.
他当场目睹一切
Poor kid watched the whole thing happen in front of him.
瞧他脸上的表情
Look at the look on the face.
和在市政府时一样
It was the same in front of City Hall.
这种事对孩子的影响会有多大?
What do you suppose something like this does to a kid?
瓦尔
Vale
别太感性了!
Don't get personal!
阿福
Alfred
我父母的档案弄到了吗?
Did you get the file on my parents?
全在你桌上
It's on your table, sir.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你想些什么 阿福?
What's on your mind, Alfred?
我不想在余年
I have no wish to fill my few remaining years...
再为朋友的死伤神
grieving for the loss of old friends...
或者朋友的儿子
or their sons.
两百周年纪念活动 无限延期
The 200th anniversary birthday gala has been indefinitely postponed.
我们无力保证大众的安全
We simply cannot guarantee public safety...
我是丑客
Joker here.
有干扰 通知人去修
We got interference. Call the OB unit.
你们说了些丑话
Now you fellows have said some pretty mean things...
有些是真的
some of which were true...
由那个魔头 格里森口中说出
under that fiend, Boss Grissom.
他是个贼 也是恐怖份子
He was a thief and a terrorist.
不过嘛 他的歌声很美
On the other hand, he had a tremendous singing voice.
他已经作古了 并交我接管
He's dead now, and he's left me in charge.
我可能有点戏剧化
Now, I can be theatrical...
也或许凶了点
and maybe even a little rough.
不过我绝不是个
But one thing I am not...
杀人凶手!
is a killer!
我是个艺术家
I'm an artist.
我喜欢派对
I love a good party.
和谈
So, truce.
周年庆照常举行!
Commence au festival!
我有个惊喜送哥谭市民
And I've got a surprise for Gotham City.
今天午夜我要当众洒下
At midnight, I will dump $20 million in cash...
两千万美元
on the crowd.
不用担心 我多的是钱
Don't worry about me. I've got enough.
我们绝不谈条件
We are not prepared to discuss any deals.
各位听到了 两千万哪
You heard it, folks, $20 million.
还有余兴节目
And there will be entertainment.
生死决战 一边是我 另一边是
The big dukeroo. With me in one corner, and in the other corner...
给哥谭市制造恐怖的人
the man who has brought real terror to Gotham City...
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
你听到了吧?
Can you hear me?
你我俩决战
Just the two of us.
空手单挑
Mano y mano.
我以真面目相见
I have taken off my make-up.
看你
Let's see...
有没有种
if you can take off yours.
告诉我 小鬼
Tell me, kid.
你曾在月光下和魔鬼共舞过吗?
You ever dance with the devil by the pale moonlight?
快走!
Let's go!
快走 杰克!
Let's go, Jack!
后会有期
See you around, kid.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗨
Hi.
我疯了吗
Tell me if I'm crazy.
今晚与过去不一样吧?
But that wasn't just another night for either of us, was it?
我是说 我们拥有对方是吗?
I mean, we both got to each other, didn't we?
为何不接受我?
Why won't you let me in?
为什么?
Why?
我接受了
You got in.
第一次见面我就爱上了你
I've loved you since I met you.
但我想不透这一切 真的不懂
But I don't know what to think of all this. I really don't.
有时候连我也一样
Sometimes I don't know what to think about this.
我势必要做的事
It's just something I have to do.
为什么?
Why?
因为没有别人能
Because nobody else can.
我企图逃避这一切 但我没办法
I tried to avoid all this, but I can't.
事情就是如此
This is how it is.
世界并不完美
It's not a perfect world.
世界不必非完美不可
It doesn't have to be a perfect world.
我只想知道 我们是否要彼此相爱?
I just gotta know, are we going to try to love each other?
我愿意一试
I'd like to.
他还在外面猖狂
But he's out there right now.
我得做事了
And I've got to go to work.
上天吧 小飞人!
Into the air, Junior Birdman!
失手了!
Missed me!
瞧我的!
Yeah! Watch me!
快点拍
Get them. Take the pictures.
哥谭市民贪婪图
Gotham's greed.
各位乡亲父老
And now, folks...
该选最信任的人的时候了?
it's time for, "Who Do You Trust?"
钱钱钱呀! 你们信任谁?
Money, money! Who do you trust?
我吗? 我无条件洒钞票呀
Me? I'm giving away free money.
而蝙蝠侠呢?
And where is the Batman?
他却在家里 洗丝袜
He's at home, washing his tights.
大苍蝇夜空翱翔 却发现我早胸有成竹
Winged battle flies through the night and finds me ready.
巴勃 面罩
Bob. Mask.
面罩! 戴面罩!
Masks! Put them on now!
现在
And now...
是我要
comes the part...
拯救你们
where I relieve you, the little people...
于无意义生活
of the burden of your failed...
的时候了
and useless lives.
正如我的美容师说的:"既然非死不可
But, as my plastic surgeon always said, "If you got to go...
就带着笑走"
go with a smile."
我的天!
Oh, my God!
是毒气
Smylex gas.
他要毒死大家!
He's going to kill everybody!
上车! 上车!
Get in the car. Get in the car!
快呀!
Hurry!
我的汽球!
My balloons!
是我的汽球!
Those are my balloons!
他偷我的汽球!
He stole my balloons!
为什么没人告诉我 他有那玩意?
Why didn't somebody tell me he had one of those things?
巴勃 枪
Bob. Gun.
给我一两分钟时间
I'm going to need a minute or two alone, boys.
快滚开!
Come on, get out of here!
来呀 你这畜牲 过来呀
Come on, you gruesome son of a bitch. Come to me.
亲爱的
Darling.
我得准时送你去教堂
I've got to get you to the church on time.
什么事?
Yes, sir?
哥谭市大教堂 两人份交通工具
Gotham City Cathedral. Transportation for two.
- 马上来? - 5分钟
- Right away, sir? - Five minutes.
- 还是10分钟吧 - 好的 就10分钟
- Better make it 10. - Okay, 10 minutes.
到了 我们走 老兄 我们走
All right, let's go, men, let's go.
你们去那边 剩下的 跟我走
You men go that way. Rest of you, follow me.
走吧
Let's go.
探照灯对着塔台 马上! 快!
Point those searchlights up at the tower, right now! Move!
说我有点阿达的确不假
It can be truly said that I have a bat in my belfry.
跳支舞吧?
Shall we dance?
没有你
You know, without you...
我的日子怎么过
I just wouldn't want to go on.
我俩是天作之合
It's as though we were made for each other.
美女与野兽
Beauty and the Beast.
如果有人当你是野兽的话
Of course, if anyone else calls you "beast"...
老子就挖出他的内脏
I'll rip their lungs out.
丑客先生?
Mr. Joker?
你说话真动听
You say such beautiful things.
而你又如此强壮有力 一身大紫!
And you're so powerful. And purple!
我喜欢紫色!
I love purple!
对不起
Excuse me.
可曾在月光下和魔鬼共舞?
Have you ever danced with the devil in the pale moonlight?
我要你的命
I'm going to kill you.
白痴!
You idiot!
是你害的 记得吧?
You made me, remember?
你把我丢进硫酸中的!
You dropped me into that vat of chemicals!
我再努力也无法忘怀这一切!
That wasn't easy to get over! And don't think that I didn't try.
是你做的
I know you did.
你杀了我父母
You killed my parents.
什么?
What?
你说什么?
What are you talking about?
我害了你 不过最初是你害我的
I made you, you made me first.
我当初只是个小孩
Hey, bat-brain, I was a kid when I killed your parents.
我说你害我 你说我害你
When I say I made you, you gotta say you made me.
我俩真幼稚?
How childish can you get?
你不会打戴眼镜人吧?
You wouldn't hit a guy with glasses on, would you?
你笑什么?
What are you laughing at?
我帮忙你
Here, let me lend you a hand.
伸出援手
Lend you a hand.
现在人最会偷工减料了!
They don't make them like they used to!
蝙仔!
Hey, Batsy!
他在那! 在下面! 降低!
There he is! Down there! Go down!
我该下台了
It's time to retire.
有空随时来玩
Feel free to drop in.
有时真会笑死我!
Sometimes I just kill myself!
快点
Come on.
抓稳!
Hold on!
警方已将丑客的人 一网打尽
Our police have rounded up all the Joker's men.
犯罪组织已消灭了
The reign of crime is over.
哥谭市的治安 已不再是笑柄了
Public safety in Gotham City is no longer a laughing matter.
你不要采访记者招待会吗?
Aren't you covering this press conference?
不要
No.
我们的普立兹奖呢?
What about our Pulitzer Prize?
我们的事呢?
What about us?
你说的蝙蝠侠照片呢?
What about your picture of Batman?
保重罗
Take care, Allie.
我们收到蝙蝠侠的信了
We've received a letter from Batman this morning.
"请转告哥谭市民
"Please inform the citizens of Gotham...
哥谭市已无犯罪事件
that Gotham City's earned a rest from crime.
万一歹徒敢再蠢动的话
But if the forces of evil should rise again...
为害哥谭市
to cast a shadow on the heart of the city...
请通知我"
call me."
请问 如何通知他?
Question. How do we call him?
他要我们放出讯号
He gave us a signal.
还是喝香槟比较适合
I thought champagne would be in order, ma'am.
嗨 阿福
Hi, Alfred.
韦恩先生要我转告你
Mr. Wayne told me to tell you...
他可能稍晚一点
that he might be a little late.
我一点也不觉意外
I'm not a bit surprised.